Want some tea?
The peach-shaped teapot in this display case
is just the thing for serving it.
It was made during the reign
of the emperor Kangxi,
from 1662 to 1722,
the very same period in which I was created
in the city of Jingdezhen,
the porcelain capital of China.
Do you know how to fill this teapot?
There’s no opening on the top, quite puzzling, isn’t it?
To discover its secret, you must turn it upside down.
There you’ll find the opening used to pour in the tea.
These ingenious teapots became fashionable in China
from the late Ming dynasty onward,
around the seventeenth century.
Now, notice its shape: the peach.
This fruit is one of the most auspicious
symbols in Chinese culture.
Legend tells that in the garden
of the Queen Mother
of the West,
a divine tree bears peaches
that grant
immortality to those
who eat them.
Chinese art is filled with symbols of the
eternal quest for immortality.
Just look at the object I hold in my hand, a - ruyi scepter,
another emblem of longevity and good fortune.
And on the teapot itself,
you can see
yet another sign of immortality:
the crane bird,
who according to legend is said to live 1000 years.