Look at the fantastic birds painted on the plate in the display case, with their long feathered tails,
aren't they magnificent?
In Japanese art, they are known as ‘hoo’
often translated as phoenix.
This mythical bird comes from China, where it is often shown together with me - the dragon
symbolising the empress and the emperor.
The bird was seen as a sign of good fortune and was said only to descend from heaven
when the empire was ruled with virtue.
These beliefs later spread to Japan.
The use of the phoenix in Japanese art dates back to the Asuka period, around the 6th to 7th century.
On the dish you see here, the birds are shown among flowers and leaves from the paulownia tree
said to be the tree where the phoenix lived.
Together, they may symbolize marital harmony, making this a fitting wedding gift.
To create this design, the artist painted the blue areas with cobalt pigment.
The piece was then glazed and fired, before adding the red, green, and purple colours.
A second firing completed the decoration.