Have you looked carefully
at the large
bowl in this display case?
It is beautifully painted
with gold pigment,
showing a classic Chinese
river landscape.
You can see the
mountains and trees,
a fisherman in his boat
and someone crossing
a small bridge.
Just the kind of peaceful of setting where a scholar like me
would feel most at ease,
reciting a poem along the riverbank.
Long ago, in the early
years of my life,
I tried to become a
government official.
But I failed miserably and
abandoned court politics
for a tranquil life and in time,
I became one of the
Eight Immortals.
But let us not wander too
far from the bowl!
Notice how the gold
pigment shines
so vividly against the soft
blue background.
To create this speckled
blue effect,
craftsmen blew cobalt
pigment through
a bamboo tube covered
with gauze onto the surface
of the unglazed vessel.
Imagine the skill and patience
that were required!
It was also a costly process,
the bowl had to be fired
several times,
and gold pigment was an expensive material.
This type of porcelain is
characteristic of the reign
of Emperor Kangxi and was made in the early 18th century.