Let’s talk about me!
I may be small, but I stand
for great strength.
Tigers aren’t actually native
to Japan,
and the artist who made me
had certainly never seen one in real life.
Still, tigers often appear
in Japanese art,
usually looking rather catlike
and even friendly.
Artists were inspired by images
from China and Korea,
where real tigers did roam.
Traditionally, I represent
one of the four
cardinal directions:
the Blue Dragon of the East,
the White Tiger of the West,
the Red Phoenix of the South,
and the Black Tortoise entwined
with a Serpent of the North.
You can see my companions
depicted on some of the
other objects nearby.
Together, we protect the universe
and ward off evil.
I’m made of porcelain, painted in
delicate cobalt blue.
Look closely, and you’ll notice
the artist even painted
each strand of my fur!
I’m a fine example of
Hirado ware,
a type of porcelain that became
popular in Japan
from the late 18th century,
known for its small,
finely detailed figures.