Have you noticed the magnificent sculpture
depicting a man on horseback?
See how he leans out from
his saddle
once holding something
in his hand.
A polo stick! Yes, you heard
that right.
Polo was already played in China
during the eighth century.
It was known as - jiqiu,
meaning “strike ball,”
and was a popular pastime
at the imperial court.
Even women were allowed
to take part in the game.
In fact, during the Tang
dynasty, women
enjoyed greater freedom
than in many other periods
of Chinese history.
Horses were highly valued
admired for their strength
and endurance.
They served both in the
military and
in leisure pursuits such
as hunting and polo.
But owning a horse was
not for everyone;
it depended on one’s rank
and status in society.
The ceramic horse you see
here was likely made
for the tomb of a wealthy individual.
It would have been placed
alongside other objects
that symbolized the deceased’s
status and power
believed to be essential
companions in the afterlife.
Even in my own time,
during the Han dynasty,
more than two thousand
years ago,
such traditions were already
well established.
But since I became an immortal,
it is something I never had
to worry about.